A Guide to the Papers of Robert L. Auldridge 1932-1936
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Robert L. Auldridge 1932-1936
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
11246
Forty-six drawings, sketches and watercolors.
Auldridge's papers consist chiefly of his student drawings and sketches. There are also watercolors of the Josiah Beers family tree, and of several proposed buildings.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
The Auldridge papers are a gift from Richard Hefner, West Virginia, 1996.
Scope and Content Information
Virginia architect Robert L. Auldridge's papers consist chiefly of his student drawings and sketches. The majority are charcoal studies of architectural details and perspectives, still lifes and the human figure.
There are also watercolors of a family tree of the descendants of Josiah Beers and several proposed buildings including a Union Pacific railroad terminal, a summer art colony, a trade school and a dancing casino. The only identified building is of a school at Riverton, Warren County, Va.
Arrangement
Arranged chronologically and alphabetically by medium.
Contents List
- Charcoal Drawings (Folder 1)
  - Geometric Shapes 1933 Apr 6, 15, 27, n.d., 5 drawings (Folder 1)
  - Chair 1933 May 4 (Folder 1)
  - "Stills" 1933 May 11 (Folder 1)
  - Jugs 1933 May 18 (Folder 1)
  - Flower & Petal Studies 1933 Nov 16, Dec 7, n.d., 4 drawings (Folder 1)
  - Lip & Eye Study 1934 Jan 16 (Folder 1)
  - Fist 1934 Jan 26 (Folder 1)
  - Foot 1934 Feb 13 (Folder 1)
  - Male Head 1934 Feb 20, Mar 8, n.d., 3 drawings (Folder 1)
  - Unidentified Shape 1934 Mar 13 (Folder 1)
  - Classical Female Head Study "Goddess" 1934 Mar 13 (Folder 1)
  - Classical Male Head Study 1934 Apr 12 (Folder 1)
  - "Greek Statue" 1934 May 22 (Folder 1)
  - Door Knocker 1934 May 24 (Folder 1)
  - Directional shading n.d. (Folder 1)
  - Architectural Forms n.d., 2 drawings (Folder 1)
- Pen & Ink and Watercolor Drawings (Folder 2)
  - Various Practice Figures & Perspectives - Pen & Ink 1932 Sep 28; 1933 Apr 25, May 16, 3 drawings (Folder 2)
  - Monument Perspectives - Pen & Ink 1933 Apr 11, 18, May 16, 3 drawings (Folder 2)
  - Room Perspective - Pen & Ink 1933 May 2 (Folder 2)
  - Geometric Shapes - Watercolor n.d. (Folder 2)
  - House Watercolors n.d., 2 drawings (Folder 2)
- Miscellaneous Media (Folder 3)
  - Window Design - Watercolor 1932 Nov 27 (Folder 3)
  - "Dancing Casino" - watercolor 1934 May (Folder 3)
  - Architectural Drawing of School Building, Riverton, Warren County, Virginia 1936 Jun, Sheet No. 2 (Folder 3)
    Designed by Eubank & Caldwell, but redrawn by R.L. Auldridge
  - "A Church for summer Colony" - watercolor n.d. (Folder 3)
  - Columns - pen & ink drawing n.d. (Folder 3)
  - "Exhibition" - watercolor n.d. (Folder 3)
  - "Family Tree" (the descendants of Josiah Beers, 1693) - pen & ink watercolor n.d. (Folder 3)
  - "Railroad Building" - watercolor n.d. (Folder 3)
  - "Summer Art Colony Plan" - watercolor n.d. (Folder 3)
  - "A Trade School" - watercolor n.d. (Folder 3)